<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Liu&#39;s Natural Way Health Center</title>
    <link>https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Liu&#39;s Natural Way Health Center</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How is Chinese medicine formulated according to the constitution?</title>
      <link>https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/blog/2024/05/01/how-is-chinese-medicine-formulated-according-to-the-constitution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/blog/2024/05/01/how-is-chinese-medicine-formulated-according-to-the-constitution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/liusnaturalway/docs/chinese-herbal-medicine/&#34;&gt;Chinese medicine formulations&lt;/a&gt; are tailored to individual constitutions based on the principles of traditional Chinese medicine (TCM), which emphasizes syndrome differentiation and treatment. TCM practitioners consider various factors, including the individual&amp;rsquo;s physical, emotional, and environmental conditions, to create personalized formulas. Here&amp;rsquo;s how this process generally works:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1syndrome-differentiation&#34;&gt;1.Syndrome Differentiation:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first step is to diagnose the individual&amp;rsquo;s current health condition, or &amp;ldquo;syndrome,&amp;rdquo; through a comprehensive assessment that includes looking at the tongue,脉搏 diagnosis, and asking detailed questions about symptoms, lifestyle, and medical history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is acupuncture treatment safe for pregnant women?</title>
      <link>https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/blog/2024/02/09/is-acupuncture-treatment-safe-for-pregnant-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/blog/2024/02/09/is-acupuncture-treatment-safe-for-pregnant-women/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/liusnaturalway/docs/acupuncture/&#34;&gt;Acupuncture&lt;/a&gt; during pregnancy is considered safe when performed by a licensed and experienced practitioner. However, there are certain precautions and &amp;ldquo;forbidden points&amp;rdquo; that should be avoided to prevent any potential risks to the pregnancy. Here are some key points regarding the safety of acupuncture for pregnant women:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Professional Training and Supervision: It is crucial that acupuncture is performed by practitioners who are well-trained in obstetric acupuncture. They should be aware of the specific needs and potential risks associated with pregnant patients&#xA;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Systematic Reviews on Safety: A systematic review of adverse events associated with acupuncture treatment during pregnancy found that when correctly applied, acupuncture is associated with few adverse events. The most common mild adverse events were needling pain, and severe adverse events or deaths were few and considered unlikely to have been caused by acupuncture&#xA;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Guidelines on Basic Training and Safety: The World Health Organization (WHO) provides guidelines on basic training and safety in acupuncture, emphasizing the importance of proper training and the knowledge of appropriate techniques and points to avoid during pregnancy&#xA;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Common Conditions Treated: Acupuncture is often used to treat common conditions during pregnancy such as nausea and vomiting, back pain, pelvic pain, constipation, and headaches&#xA;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Contraindicated Points: There are specific acupuncture points that are generally avoided during pregnancy due to their potential to stimulate uterine contractions or have other effects that could be harmful. Some of these points include Large Intestine 4 (LI4), Stomach 36 (ST36), Spleen 6 (SP6), Bladder 67 (BL67), and Bladder 32 (BL32)&#xA;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Risks and Side Effects: While acupuncture is generally safe, there are potential risks and side effects such as infection, organ puncture, and nerve damage. These risks can be minimized by using sterile, disposable needles and by having the treatment performed by a qualified practitioner&#xA;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Insurance Coverage: Some insurance companies may have specific exclusions for certain procedures related to pregnancy, such as turning breech babies or inducing labor, but overall, acupuncture during pregnancy is considered a safe form of treatment&#xA;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Expert Opinion: Experts in the field consider obstetric acupuncture to be extremely safe, especially when compared to other modalities, and when performed by well-trained practitioners&#xA;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to note that while acupuncture can be a safe and effective treatment for many conditions during pregnancy, it should always be performed by a professional who is experienced in working with pregnant women and is aware of the specific precautions and techniques necessary for a safe treatment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are the dietary contraindications to be aware of during Tuina treatment?</title>
      <link>https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/blog/2023/11/28/what-are-the-dietary-contraindications-to-be-aware-of-during-tuina-treatment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/blog/2023/11/28/what-are-the-dietary-contraindications-to-be-aware-of-during-tuina-treatment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During &lt;a href=&#34;https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/docs/acupressure-tuina/&#34;&gt;Tuina treatment&lt;/a&gt;, which is a traditional Chinese medical therapy involving manipulation of the body, it&amp;rsquo;s important to pay attention to certain dietary contraindications to ensure the safety and effectiveness of the treatment. Here are some dietary considerations to keep in mind during Tuina treatment:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Avoid Eating Immediately After Treatment: It&amp;rsquo;s recommended to wait for a while before eating after Tuina to prevent increasing the burden on the gastrointestinal tract, which could lead to nausea or vomiting. Generally, it&amp;rsquo;s advised to wait at least half an hour before eating.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Light Diet: After Tuina, it&amp;rsquo;s best to consume a light diet and avoid cold, greasy, spicy, or irritating foods to promote recovery and reduce irritation to the digestive system.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stay Hydrated: Tuina can accelerate blood circulation and metabolism, leading to the loss of some body fluids. Therefore, it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to drink a glass of warm boiled water after treatment to replenish fluids.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Avoid Cold Drinks: After Tuina, the pores of the body are open, making it easier to catch a cold. It&amp;rsquo;s important to avoid cold drinks to prevent catching a chill.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Avoid Overeating Before Treatment: It&amp;rsquo;s best not to eat too much before Tuina as a full stomach can cause drowsiness, and the stomach and intestines are working on digestion. Tuina treatment can affect the digestive process if performed immediately after a heavy meal.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6.Avoid Being Too Hungry: Being too hungry before Tuina can lead to dizziness or hypoglycemia during the treatment. It&amp;rsquo;s important to have some food in your stomach before undergoing treatment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do the curative effects of Chinese herbal medicine differ from modern medicine?</title>
      <link>https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/blog/2023/08/03/how-do-the-curative-effects-of-chinese-herbal-medicine-differ-from-modern-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/blog/2023/08/03/how-do-the-curative-effects-of-chinese-herbal-medicine-differ-from-modern-medicine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The curative effects of &lt;a href=&#34;https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/liusnaturalway/docs/chinese-herbal-medicine/&#34;&gt;Chinese herbal medicine&lt;/a&gt; and modern medicine differ in several fundamental ways, reflecting distinct medical philosophies and approaches to treatment:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1philosophical-approach&#34;&gt;1.Philosophical Approach:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chinese Herbal Medicine: Emphasizes holistic healing and the balance of energies within the body. It views illness as a sign of imbalance and aims to restore harmony and the body&amp;rsquo;s self-healing abilities.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Modern Medicine: Focuses on etiology and symptom relief. It often targets specific pathogens or disease mechanisms with precise interventions such as synthetic drugs or surgical procedures.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2mode-of-treatment&#34;&gt;2.Mode of Treatment:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chinese Herbal Medicine: Typically uses natural plant, animal, or mineral substances that may contain multiple active ingredients, working on multiple physiological pathways simultaneously.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Modern Medicine: Employs synthetic drugs that are designed to target specific molecular targets with defined mechanisms of action.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;3speed-of-efficacy&#34;&gt;3.Speed of Efficacy:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chinese Herbal Medicine: May have a slower onset of action because it often works through adjusting the body&amp;rsquo;s inherent balance.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Modern Medicine: Can provide rapid relief, especially for acute conditions, as synthetic drugs can quickly address symptoms.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;4side-effects&#34;&gt;4.Side Effects:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chinese Herbal Medicine: Side effects can be less predictable due to complex的成分 interactions but are generally considered mild and less likely to cause severe adverse reactions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Modern Medicine: Synthetic drugs may have well-defined side effects that are thoroughly studied during drug development and listed in the drug&amp;rsquo;s documentation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;5personalized-treatment&#34;&gt;5.Personalized Treatment:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chinese Herbal Medicine: Places a strong emphasis on tailoring treatments to individual differences such as constitution, age, gender, etc.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Modern Medicine: While also moving towards personalized medicine, treatments are often based on disease type and pathological state.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;6long-term-efficacy-and-prevention&#34;&gt;6.Long-term Efficacy and Prevention:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chinese Herbal Medicine: May be more effective for long-term health maintenance and disease prevention by focusing on enhancing the body&amp;rsquo;s natural defenses.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Modern Medicine: More effective in acute disease treatment and symptom control.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;7evidence-base&#34;&gt;7.Evidence Base:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chinese Herbal Medicine: Although it has a history of thousands of years of use, scientific evidence for its efficacy is relatively scarce, and many herbal remedies need to be validated through modern scientific research.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Modern Medicine: Its efficacy is usually based on rigorous scientific experiments and clinical trials, providing a more substantial evidence base.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;8cultural-and-philosophical-roots&#34;&gt;8.Cultural and Philosophical Roots:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chinese Herbal Medicine: Deeply rooted in Eastern culture and philosophy, particularly the concepts of Yin and Yang and the Five Elements in Traditional Chinese Medicine.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Modern Medicine: Based on Western scientific methods and evidence-based medicine.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-summary&#34;&gt;In summary,&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the differences in curative effects between &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/docs/chinese-herbal-medicine/&#34;&gt;Chinese herbal medicine&lt;/a&gt; and modern medicine reflect different medical philosophies and treatment approaches. Both have unique strengths and limitations, and in many cases, combining the advantages of both can provide a more comprehensive treatment plan for patients.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which patients are not suitable for Tuina?</title>
      <link>https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/blog/2023/08/03/which-patients-are-not-suitable-for-tuina/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/blog/2023/08/03/which-patients-are-not-suitable-for-tuina/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/docs/acupressure-tuina/&#34;&gt;Tuina treatment&lt;/a&gt; is generally considered safe and effective for a variety of conditions, but there are certain patient groups and conditions where it may not be suitable. According to the search results and various studies, here are some patients and conditions for which Tuina treatment may be contraindicated or require special consideration:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Severe Rheumatic, Neurological, Cardiovascular, and Metabolic Disorders: Patients with known severe rheumatic, neurological, cardiovascular, and metabolic disorders are often excluded from studies on Tuina treatment&#xA;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serious Spinal Pathology: Patients with serious spinal pathologies such as malignancy, inflammatory or infective diseases, cauda equina syndrome, fractures, spinal stenosis, spondylolisthesis, or nerve root compromise are typically not suitable for Tuina treatment&#xA;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pregnant Women: Women who are pregnant, lactating, or planning to conceive within the next 6 months are usually excluded from studies involving Tuina treatment&#xA;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;History of Spinal Surgery: Patients with a history of spinal surgery or those scheduled for major surgery within the next 6 months are often not considered suitable for Tuina treatment&#xA;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Uncontrollable Cognitive Impairment or Mental Disorder: Patients with severe cognitive impairment or mental disorders such as severe depressive disorder or schizophrenia are generally not suitable for Tuina treatment&#xA;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Contraindications to Tuina Manipulation: Patients with conditions like severe osteoporosis, infectious diseases, and skin disorders in the lumbar region are not suitable for Tuina treatment&#xA;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Participation in Other Clinical Trials: Patients who have participated in other clinical trials related to low back pain within the past 3 months are usually excluded from Tuina treatment studies&#xA;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Skin Conditions: Patients with skin conditions such as phlebitis, open wounds, fractures, or tissue damage in the area to be manipulated are not suitable for Tuina treatment&#xA;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;9&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Complications: Patients with complications like severe dehydration, metabolic acidosis, disorders of consciousness, seizures, twitching, shock, or azotemia should not receive Tuina treatment&#xA;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to note that the safety and suitability of Tuina treatment can vary depending on the specific condition of the patient and the expertise of the practitioner. Always consult with a qualified healthcare provider before undergoing Tuina or any other form of treatment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can acupuncture help relieve anxiety during pregnancy?</title>
      <link>https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/blog/2023/06/05/can-acupuncture-help-relieve-anxiety-during-pregnancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/blog/2023/06/05/can-acupuncture-help-relieve-anxiety-during-pregnancy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/liusnaturalway/docs/acupuncture/&#34;&gt;Acupuncture&lt;/a&gt; has shown some effectiveness in alleviating anxiety during pregnancy. According to a study, acupuncture can reduce perceived stress and improve anxiety symptoms in pregnant women. The study involved 56 pregnant women who underwent six sessions of acupuncture, and the results indicated a significant decrease in stress scores across several measures, including feelings of unease, lack of control, tension, fatigue, anger, and the inability to cope with stress. Additionally, acupuncture significantly improved scores related to perceived control over the situation, and there was a noticeable difference in the average perceived stress from the initial session to the sessions held in the first, second, and third weeks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are the potential risks and side effects of acupuncture treatment compared to medication?</title>
      <link>https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/blog/2022/04/07/what-are-the-potential-risks-and-side-effects-of-acupuncture-treatment-compared-to-medication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/blog/2022/04/07/what-are-the-potential-risks-and-side-effects-of-acupuncture-treatment-compared-to-medication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/liusnaturalway/docs/acupuncture/&#34;&gt;Acupuncture treatment&lt;/a&gt; is generally considered safe when performed by a licensed and trained practitioner using sterile, disposable needles. However, like any medical intervention, acupuncture does carry some potential risks and side effects, which can be compared to those of medication. Here are some potential risks and side effects associated with acupuncture treatment:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Local Adverse Events: These are the most common and typically include minor issues such as local bleeding, pain or tenderness at the needle site, local burns from moxibustion, and local bruising&#xA;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Systemic Reactions: Some patients may experience systemic reactions such as dizziness or syncope, nausea and vomiting, and in rare cases, more severe reactions like infections&#xA;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Infections: Although rare, infections can occur if the needles are not sterile or if the acupuncture site is not properly cleaned after treatment. Infections were reported in 19 studies, but all patients recovered after appropriate treatment&#xA;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Organ or Tissue Injury: Accidental puncture of organs or tissues can happen, especially if the acupuncture is performed near vital structures. This has been reported in 233 systematic reviews (SRs)&#xA;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Neurovascular Injury: There is a risk of damaging nerves or blood vessels, which can lead to serious complications, although this is very rare.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pneumothorax: A rare but serious risk associated with acupuncture, especially when performed in the chest area, is the risk of pneumothorax, or collapsed lung&#xA;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Allergic Reactions: Some individuals may have an allergic reaction to the materials used in the acupuncture needles.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;needle breakage: This is a rare event but can cause serious complications if the needle fragments remain in the body.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;9&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Infection Risk: As with any invasive procedure, there is a risk of infection if proper hygiene and sterilization techniques are not followed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;10&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Interactions with Medications: Acupuncture may interact with certain medications, which could potentially alter their effectiveness or lead to adverse effects.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Compared to medication, acupuncture generally has fewer side effects and is less likely to cause systemic adverse reactions. However, it&amp;rsquo;s important to note that the side effects of medication can range from mild to severe and can include a wide range of physiological effects depending on the drug and the individual&amp;rsquo;s response to it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who is not suitable for cupping?</title>
      <link>https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/blog/2022/04/07/who-is-not-suitable-for-cupping/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/blog/2022/04/07/who-is-not-suitable-for-cupping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cn3c3p.github.io/liusnaturalway/liusnaturalway/docs/cupping-therapy/&#34;&gt;Cupping therapy&lt;/a&gt;, a traditional treatment method widely used in Asian countries, particularly in traditional Chinese medicine, has been subject to various systematic reviews to assess its effectiveness and safety. While cupping therapy is beneficial for certain conditions, there are specific patient groups and situations where it may not be suitable or could pose potential risks. According to the search results and clinical evidence, the following patients or conditions are not suitable for cupping therapy:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
